<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Zhiwei Peng</title>
 <link href="http://zhiwei-peng.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://zhiwei-peng.com/"/>
 <updated>2016-06-12T23:50:07-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://zhiwei-peng.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Zhiwei Peng</name>
   <email>zwpeng1@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Studying swimming sandfish and beating flagella at UBC</title>
   <link href="http://zhiwei-peng.com/2016/05/25/UBC/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://zhiwei-peng.com/2016/05/25/UBC</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I did my master at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ubc.ca/&quot;&gt;University of British Columbia&lt;/a&gt; in the beautiful city of Vancouver and graduated in May 2016. I loved my experience at UBC, studying and modeling biological locomotion from the underground swimming of sandfish lizards (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scincus_scincus&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scincus scincus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) in sand to the microscopic motion of a flagellated bacteria in a viscous fluid. During my time at UBC, I presented at an academic conference (&lt;a href=&quot;http://meetings.aps.org/link/BAPS.2015.DFD.L26.4&quot;&gt;DFD2015&lt;/a&gt;) for the first time of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;swimming-sandfish-lizards&quot;&gt;Swimming sandfish lizards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might wonder why would I use the word &lt;em&gt;swimming&lt;/em&gt; for an animal that has four limbs which can be used for walking, or crawling? It turns out that in order to prevent overheating or escape potential threat, sandfish can dive into sand. When it burrows into sand, a sandfish usually moves by propagating a deformation wave along its body while putting its limbs alongside its body&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. So swimming it is, and which is also how this desert lizard got its name &lt;em&gt;sandfish&lt;/em&gt; according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scincus_scincus&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;font-size:80%;color:gray;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sandfishWiki.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;sandfish &quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
A captive juvenile male sandfish skink. CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this paper by &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/325/5938/314&quot;&gt;Maladen &lt;em&gt;et. al.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and references therein or watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Xzt1iJbwNXE&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; interesting interview on YouTube for details on sandfish swimming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in this motion, we developed a mathematical model which employs a drag law developed by Maladen &lt;em&gt;et. al.&lt;/em&gt; to characterize the swimming behavior of a sandfish lizard that is modeled as a slender filament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I presented our findings at the APS DFD meeting in Boston in November 2015, which is the first time I’ve ever attended an academic conference. I was amazed at the sheer number of researchers working in fluid related fields. My slides for the talk can be found &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/DFD2015.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. My paper can be found &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pof1.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The following image is an animation of two simulations of our model sandfish swimmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;font-size:80%;color:gray;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/sandfish.gif&quot; alt=&quot;sandfish swimming&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Numerical simulation of two model sandfish swimmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beating-flagella&quot;&gt;Beating flagella&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though invisible to the naked eye, the world of microorganisms is very fascinating.  The ability to move around in a surrounding fluid is critical for microorganisms to function. For example, a sperm has to swim upstream to fertilize an egg. The animation below shows how sperms move around in a fluid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;font-size:80%;color:gray;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/SpermChemo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;sperm swimming &quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Swimming sperms, adapted from Armon L, Eisenbach M&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; CC BY 2.5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As can be seen from the animation, a sperm moves around in a similar fashion to that of a sand-swimming lizard. It passes a deformation wave along its hair-like appendage, which is called flagellum. The swimming behavior of a flagellum in various settings has been extensively studied in the literature, whether numerically, analytically or experimentally. In my project, I looked at the possibility of having a non-uniform flexibility distribution along the flagellum so that its propulsive force can be improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I wrote this post to conclude my study at UBC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/325/5938/314&quot;&gt;Undulatory Swimming in Sand: Subsurface Locomotion of the Sandfish Lizard&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0028359&quot;&gt;Behavioral Mechanism during Human Sperm Chemotaxis: Involvement of Hyperactivation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Paper featured in CSME Bulletin</title>
   <link href="http://zhiwei-peng.com/2016/05/13/CSME-feature/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://zhiwei-peng.com/2016/05/13/CSME-feature</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The paper &lt;em&gt;Characteristics of undulatory locomotion in granular media&lt;/em&gt; is featured in the CSME&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:footnote&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Bulletin research highlights. In this paper, we developed a mathematical model to investigate the swimming characteristics of a sandfish lizard (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scincus_scincus&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scincus scincus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) in granular media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ultimately their research helps to understand how we can design biomimetic
robots capable of efficient and precisely controlled motion through challenging environments,
such as sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the CSME Bulletin &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csme-scgm.ca/sites/all/themes/csme/uploaded/CSME_publications/BULLETIN-SPRING%202016.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (page 12). &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pof1.pdf&quot;&gt;Download a PDF&lt;/a&gt; of our paper or read it &lt;a href=&quot;http://scitation.aip.org/content/aip/journal/pof2/28/3/10.1063/1.4942895&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:footnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Canadian Society for Mechanical Engineering &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:footnote&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
