<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Zhiwei Peng</title>
 <link href="http://zhiwei-peng.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://zhiwei-peng.com/"/>
 <updated>2016-05-13T17:03:33-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://zhiwei-peng.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Zhiwei Peng</name>
   <email>zwpeng1@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Paper featured in CSME Bulletin</title>
   <link href="http://zhiwei-peng.com/2016/05/13/CSME-feature/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://zhiwei-peng.com/2016/05/13/CSME-feature</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The paper &lt;em&gt;Characteristics of undulatory locomotion in granular media&lt;/em&gt; is featured in the CSME (The Canadian Society for Mechanical Engineering) Bulletin as a research highlight. In this paper, we employed a mathematical model to investigate the swimming characteristics of a sandfish lizard in a granular media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ultimately their research helps to understand how we can design biomimetic
robots capable of efficient and precisely controlled motion through challenging environments,
such as sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the CSME Bulletin &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csme-scgm.ca/sites/all/themes/csme/uploaded/CSME_publications/BULLETIN-SPRING%202016.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (page 12). &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pof1.pdf&quot;&gt;Download a PDF&lt;/a&gt; of our paper or read it &lt;a href=&quot;http://scitation.aip.org/content/aip/journal/pof2/28/3/10.1063/1.4942895&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>About</title>
   <link href="http://zhiwei-peng.com/2016/04/19/about-me/"/>
   <updated>2016-04-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://zhiwei-peng.com/2016/04/19/about-me</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! I am a Master’s student at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubc.ca&quot;&gt;The University of British Columbia, Vancouver&lt;/a&gt; and a member of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iam.ubc.ca&quot;&gt;Institute of Applied Mathematics&lt;/a&gt;. My research is focused on bio-locomotion in fluids, a field that I find very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before UBC, I was at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buaa.edu.cn&quot;&gt;Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics&lt;/a&gt; in China as an undergrad where I studied aerodynamics and started to enjoy mathematics yet found it intriguingly profound. In order to learn more about math, I got a second degree in applied mathematics at the same university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View my LinkedIn profile &lt;a href=&quot;https://ca.linkedin.com/in/zhiweipeng&quot;&gt;@Zhiwei Peng&lt;/a&gt;. View my CV &lt;a href=&quot;/Resume&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;research-and-publications&quot;&gt;Research and Publications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on the swimming and propulsion of flexible slender bodies at low Reynolds number. See &lt;a href=&quot;/Publications&quot;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; for a list of work that have been published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many situations of biological locomotion in fluids, such as flapping birds, swimming fish and beating flagella, propulsive thrust is achieved by periodic motion of a flexible body or appendages. Elastic deformations of flexible parts on a swimmer can lead to significantly improved propulsive performance across Reynolds numbers. In this project, I am trying to look at the interesting behaviors resulting from the fluid-structure interaction of a slender filament immersed in a viscous fluid that is periodically actuated in a certain way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/r1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;aa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
